Finding Aid for Alan G. Billings set renderings, 1967-1990
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Alan G. Billings set renderings 1967-1990
Billings, Alan G.
0.3 linear feet, 1 bundle, and 2 framed drawings
2012004 Aa 2
Alan G. Billings was a set designer and professor at the University of Michigan. The collection includes painted set renderings from productions staged at the University of Michigan during his tenure.
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Donated by Alan Billings (donor no. 10703 ) in April 1999
No further additions to the records are expected.
The collection is open to research.
Alan G. Billings was born on June 29, 1929, in Atlanta, Georgia. He earned a B.F.A. from the University of Georgia in 1955 and an M.F.A. from the Carnegie Institute of Technology in 1958. Billings taught at the University of Louisville from 1958 to 1960. He also served as a Professor of the School of Music at the University of Michigan, where he taught scenic design.
The Alan G. Billings collection consists of set renderings painted by Billings while he was a professor at the University of Michigan. These renderings include both depictions of the sets, and depictions of certain aspects of production staging and costume design. The renderings are organized roughly by size, and thereunder alphabetically by title. Most set renderings also include information on where the production was staged.
Subjects - Visual Materials:
Set designers--Michigan--Ann Arbor.; Theatrical productions--Michigan--Ann Arbor.; University of Michigan--Faculty.
Genre Terms:
Set design drawings.
- Set Renderings
  - The Cherry Orchard by Anton Chekhov (costume design by James B. Harris), 1969 (Object 1)
  - The Cherry Orchard by Anton Chekhov, 1969 (Object 2)
  - The Caucasian Chalk Circle by Bertolt Brecht, 1970 (Bundle 1)
  - Hotel Paradiso by Georges Feydeau (Act II), 1969 (Bundle 1)
  - King John by William Shakespeare, 1967 (Bundle 1)
  - The Playboy of the Western World by J. M. Synge, 1967 (Bundle 1)
  - The Royal Family by George Kaufman, 1977 (Bundle 1)
  - She Stoops to Conquer by Oliver Goldsmith, 1978 (Bundle 1)
  - The Balcony by Jean Genet (2 drawings) (Box 1)
  - Born Yesterday by Garson Kanin, 1970 (Box 1)
  - Caesar and Cleopatra by G. B. Shaw, 1971 (Box 1)
  - Cat on a Hot Tin Roof by Tennessee Williams, 1983 (Box 1)
  - Cosi fan tutte by W. A. Mozart (Act II, i), 1985 (Box 1)
  - Cosi fan tutte by W. A. Mozart (Act II, ii), 1985 (Box 1)
  - Cyrano de Bergerac by Edmond Rostand (Act II) (Box 1)
  - Cyrano de Bergerac by Edmond Rostand (Act III) (Box 1)
  - Death of a Salesman by Arthur Miller, 1975 (Box 1)
  - A Little Night Music by Stephen Sondheim (Act I, ii curtain drop), 1990 (Box 1)
  - The Merchant of Venice by William Shakespeare, 1970 (Box 1)
  - The Merry Widow (Act II), 1986 by Franz Lehar (Box 1)
  - The Merry Widow (Act III), 1986 by Franz Lehar (Box 1)
  - Mother Courage and Her Children by Bertolt Brecht (Box 1)
  - Othello by William Shakespeare (Act I, ii), 1976 (Box 1)
  - The Plough and the Stars by Sean O'Casey (Box 1)
  - The Relapse by John Vanbrugh, 1980 (Box 1)
  - Serjeant Musgrave's Dance by John Arden (Box 1)
  - Tartuffe by Moliere, 1981 (Box 1)